Mss.B.C81.1
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Augustin Pyrame de Candolle, September 9, 1813; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Formerly: B C81.7.
  - Letter to [Sir] James Edward Smith, Nov. 18, 1813; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Boston, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed in part: Davis. Correa in America... APS Trans.,n.s.,45.1955, p.114.
  - Letter to Messrs. Le Roy, Boyard & McEvery, April 28, 1814; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Business.
  - Letter to Stephen Elliott, Charleston, July 13, 1814; Muhlenberg, Henry, 1753-1815
    Lancaster, Photostat of A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Botanical news. Refers to Z.Collins and Correa de Serra. From original in Arnold Arboretum, Harvard University.
  - Letter to [James Madison], Dec. 10, 1814; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 6p.and end. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed: Davis. Correa in America... APS Trans., n.s.,45, 1955, pp.132-134. From original in Library of Congress.
  - Letter to Augustin Pyrame de Candolle, April 8, 1815; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Formerly B C81.8.
  - Report of committee on a paper relative to a species of Malaxis, by W.P.S.Barton, Aug. 10, 1815; 9x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: .J.Correa de Serra and Zaccheus Collins. 2p.and end. ----Typescript. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...)
  - Letter to [Augustin Pyrame] De Candolle Montpellier, Nov. 7, 1815; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Charleston, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p.and add., end. In French. (see Correa de Serra. Letters.) Wishes him to correspond with Stephen Elliott. From original in Gray Herbarium, Harvard University.
  - Letter to [William Rawle], March 14, 1816; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Photostat of A.L.S. 4p. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed: Davis, Correa in America... APS Trans.n.s., 45, 1955, pp.145-147. (from original in University of Pennsylvania Archives.)
  - Report of committee on the memorial relative to the first discovery of the new genus of plants called Bartonia, March 15, 1816; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: J.Correa de Serra and Zaccheus Collins. 2p.and end. Publication not recommended. ----Typescript. (see Correa de Serra Letters...)
  - Letter to Deleuze, April 8, 1816; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Formerly B C81.4
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], May 12, 1816; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. (see Correa de Serra. Letters.) Introduces Col. Jones. Concerning the papers of Lewis.
  - Report of committee on the publication of William Byrd's journal of the Virginia North Carolina boundary, May 22, 1816; 6-1/2x7-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: J.Correa de Serra, Peter S. DuPonceau and C.Wistar. 1p.and end. ----Typescript. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...)
  - Letter to [André] Dashkoff, Sept. 7, 1816; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Charlottesville, photostat of A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed: Davis. Correa in America... APS Trans.,n.s., 45,1955, p.154. From original in University of Virginia library.
  - Letter to James Monroe, Oct. 12, [1816?]; 11x8-1/2; Rademaker, Joseph
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning Correa's taking over as the diplomatic representative for Portugual.
  - Letter to ----, Oct. 18, 1816; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de serra. Letters...) Asks that Vasques be appointed consul general to replace Rademaker.
  - Letter to James Monroe, Dec. 20, 1816; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 8p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Diplomatic difficulties with Portugual.
  - Letter to James Monroe, Dec. 22, 1816; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Photostat of A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed: Davis. Correa in America... APS Trans., n.s., 45, 1955, 154-155. From original in New York Public Library.
  - Letter to [James] Monroe, Jan. 16, 1817; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning a death in the royal family.
  - Letter to ----, April 25, 1817; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Diplomatic business.
  - Letter to Richard Rush, May 10, 1817; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Foreign policy of the U.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 11, 1817; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865
  - Letter to Richard Rush, May 20, 1817; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 4p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning diplomatic relations over a revolt in Brazil.
  - Letter to Richard Rush, May 25, 1817; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 5p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. letters...) Informs him of a blockade of Pernambuco
  - Letter to James Madison, June 18, 1817; 11x8-1/2; Rush, Richard
    Washington, Typed L. 10p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning Correa's official letters over the dispute with Brazil.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], July 12, 1817; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    New York, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed: Davis. Correa in America... APS Trans., n.s., 45, 1955, p.155. From original in Mass. Hist. Soc.
  - Letter to Richard Rush, July 23, 1817; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Typed L.in 3rd.P. 2p. Copy (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Has no dispatches to send.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Sept. 19, 1817; 11x8-1/2; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 4p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning teachers for various subjects for the university. Refers to Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to Thomas Cooper, Sept. 23, 1817; 11x8-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, pres.U.S., 1743-1826.
    Monticello, Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Hopes he will come to the university. Refers to Correa de Serra and Walsh.
  - Letter to [Joseph Francisco Correia de Serra?], Sept. 30, 1817; 11x8-1/2; Vasques, Joaquim Joze
    New York, Typed L. 2p. Copy. In Portuguese. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Consular business.
  - Letter to John Quincy Adams, Nov. 19, 1817; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning Portuguese foreign affairs.
  - Letter to [Robert] Walsh, Jan. 9, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Typed L. 3p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning philosophical inquiries. Concerning an article by Destutt de Tracy. Refers to Correa.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Elizabeth Mifflin] Wistar, Jan. 31, 1818; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. (see Correa de Serra. Letters.) Printed: Davis. Correa in America... APS Trans.,n.s., 45, 1955, p.160. From original in Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Feb. 20, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 3p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Thinks he may take the post at the university, due to University of Pennsylvania politics. Refers to Correa.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Q[uincy] Adams, March 8, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 2p.and enc.of 2p. copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Portuguese relations.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Quincey [sic] Adams, March 18, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Baltimore, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Is going to Norfolk for his health.
  - Letter to John Quincy Adams, March 25, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Norfolk, (?), Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de serra. Letters...) Portuguese-U.S. relations.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], April 10, 1818; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Norfolk, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed: Davis. Correa in America, APS Trans., n.s., 45, 1955, p.162. From original in Massachusetts Historical Society.
  - Letter to John Quincey [sic] Adams, April 24, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Portuguese foreign relations.
  - Necrological Note on Caspar Wistar, April 1818; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
  - Letter to J[ohn] Quincy Adams, July 30, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning consuls.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Oct. 6, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Fredericksburgh, Typed L. 3p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning the possibility of his going to the university. Refers to Ord and Wilson and Correa.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Quincy Adams, Oct. 13, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 3p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning a consul which the king wishes replaced.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Quincy Adams, Oct. 15, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, (?), Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning foreign affairs.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Quincy Adams, Oct. 18, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning a consul for the southern states.
  - Letter to Joseph Delaplaine, Philadelphia, Nov. 5, 1818; 9-3/4x8; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    FILM 54-66 FRAME 230.
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Correa de Serra papers.) Refuses compliment. Congratulates him on his Franklin.
    Formerly B C81.2.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Quincy Adams, Nov. 6, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning consuls.
  - Letter to John Quincey [sic] Adams, Nov. 13, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Foreign relations.
  - Letter to John Quincey [sic] Adams, Nov. 14, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 4p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Foreign relations.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Quincey [sic] Adams, Dec. 11, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, (?), Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Foreign relations.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Quincy Adams, Dec. 14, 1818; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Lists consuls for three posts.
  - Letter to John Quincy Adams, Feb. 4, 1819; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (See Correa de Serra. Letters...) Foreign relations.
  - Letter to John Quincy Adams, Feb. 27, 1819; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Lists consuls for Portugual.
  - Letter to J[acob] Bigelow, Boston, March 7, 1819; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed: Davis. Correa in America... APS Trans.,n.s., 45, 1955, p.168. From original in Mass.Hist.Soc.
  - Letter to John Quincy Adams, March 17, 1819; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Asks for another appointment,since he cannot meet him as planned.
  - Letter to John Quincy Adams, March 17, 1819; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Washington, Typed L. 10p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Diplomatic events with Portugual.
  - Letter to Daniel Brent, March 20, 1819; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Business.
  - Letter to ----, March 30, 1819; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Photostat of A.L. 1p. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, June 21, 1819; 11x8-1/2; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 4p. copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning the University of Virginia. Refers to J.Vaughan and Correa.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, July 28, 1819; 11x8-1/2; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Friendly letter. Concerning Collins and Nuttall. Refers to Correa.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, Sept. 13, 1819; 11x8-1/2; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Will teach in Lexington and come to Virginia next year. Refers to J.Vaughan and Correa.
  - Letter to James Madison, Montpellier, Nov. 15, 1819; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed: Davis. Correa in America... APS Trans., n.s., 45, 1955, p.173. From original in Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
  - Letter to John Quincey [sic] Adams, Nov. 23, 1819; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 5p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed: Davis. Correa in America... APS Trans.,n.s., 45, 1955, p.173.
  - Letter to Baron von Stackelberg, Washington, Dec. 8, 1819; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    New York, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Correa de Serra. Letters) Asks that he check on the delivery of certain mail for him. From original in Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
  - Memorandum pertaining to diplomacy with the U.S., 1819; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    [ca.?]. Typed D. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...)
  - Letter to John Quincey [sic] Adams, Jan. 27, 1820; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 3p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Foreign affairs.
  - Letter to Count of Palmela, March 4, 1820; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 5p. Copy. (see Correa da Serra. Letters...) Foreign affairs. For information concerning this letter see: R.B.Davis. Letters to and from... 1949-1953.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, May 3, 1820; 11x8-1/2; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Columbia, S.C., Typed L. 3p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Thinks he is settled in South Carolina. Concerning Correa.
  - Letter to Sir J[ames] E[dward] Smith, May 9, 1820; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p.,end.and add. with endorsement by George Ord. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed: Davis. Correa in America... APS Trans., n.s., 45, 1955, p.178. From original in Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Quincey [sic] Adams, June 4, 1820; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Foreign relations.
  - Letter to John Quincey [sic] Adams, June 8, 1820; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
  - Letter to [Richard Anthony Salisbury], July 4, 1820; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 6p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Botanical news. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John Quincey [sic] Adams, July 16, 1820; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Wilmington, Typed L. 3p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Foreign relations.
  - Letter to [John Wayles] Eppes, July 29, 1820; 11x8-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Typed L. 6p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning the university. Friendly letter. Correa's thoughts of Elliott.
  - Letter to Dabney Carr, Aug. 10, 1820; Gilmer, Francis Walker, 1790-1826
    Richmond, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed: Davis. Correa in America...; APS Trans., n.s., 45, 1955,178-179. From original in Va.State library.
  - Letter to John Quincy Adams, Aug. 26, 1820; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
  - Letter to John Quincy Adams, Nov. 9, 1820; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    New York, Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Has referred the question to Portugual.
  - Letter to [Joseph Francisco Correa de Serra.], Dec. 1, 1820; 9-3/4x8; American Philosophical Society
    Draft of L. 1p.and end. Testimonial of his excellence. See Proc., XXIII, pt.3,498. ---Typed copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...)
  - Letter to [Sir James Edward Smith], Jan. 1, 1821; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    London, Typed L. 1p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Will visit him in Norwich.
  - Letter to [Sir James Edward] Smith, Jan. 2, 1821; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    London, Typed L. 3p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Will be glad to help his nephew, if able.
  - Letter to [Sir James E. Smith], Jan. 10, 1821; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    London, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Must go to Paris. Will remember his nephew and help him.
  - Letter to [Sir James Edward] Smith, Feb. 20, 1821; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    London, Typed L. 4p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Will help his nephew enter trade in Brazil.
  - Letter to J[ames] E. Smith, March 1, 1821; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    London, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Will be very happy to help his nephew, if the boy can be shipped to Rio.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, March 24, 1821; 11x8-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 3p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Recommends Lardner Vanuxem as professor at the university. Refers to Correa.
  - Letter to Sir J[ames] E. Smith, July 23, 1821; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    London, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Is returning to Portugual. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to R[ichard] A. Salisbury, Sept. 3, 1821; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Lisbon, Typed L. 3p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning his return to Portugual. Botanical hopes in Portugual.
  - Newspaper clipping reporting Correia's departure from Liverpool, November 11, [1821]; Newspaper clipping
  - Journal of the travels..., 1821; 11x8-1/2; Nuttall, Thomas, 1786-1859
    Typescript of t.p. 1p. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Mentions Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to [Peter S.] DuPonceau, Jan. 12, 1822; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Lisbon, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Printed: Davis. Correa in America... APS Trans.,n.s., 45, 1955, p.185. From original in Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Rene Louis Desfontaines, August 15, 1822; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Lisbonne, ALS 1p.add. In French. Recommends son Edward, who will study medicine in Paris. Mentions "jardin des plantes."
  - Letter to [Robert] Walsh, April 5, 1823; 11x8-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Typed L. 2p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning the various requests that he write his autobiography. Refers to Correa.
  - Letter to R[ichard] A. Salisbury, London, Oct. 6, 1827; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Neufchatel en Bray, Typed L. 4p. Copy. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning his plans for the future, Refers to his father's name and fame.
  - Letter to [Richard Beale Davis], May 12, 1949; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Institut de France. Bibliothèque
    Paris, A.L.S.: Paul Cloe(?). 2p. In French. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Concerning Correa de Serra and lists letters of his available for reproduction
  - Letters to and from various persons pertaining to his research on Correa de Serra, 1949-1953; Davis, Richard Beale
    D. 11 items, Various sizes. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...)
  - Notes concerning Correa de Serra, taken from various sources, 1957; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Davis, Richard Beale
    D. 39 leaves. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...)
  - Miscellaneous notes of biographical or critical estimates of Correa de Serra, [1957]; 11x8-1/2; Davis, Richard Beale
    D. 19 leaves. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...)
  - Letter to Baron Humboldt., undated; 10x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Typed L.in 3rd.P. 1p. Copy In French. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...) Invitation to dinner.
  - The case of the Brazilian Indians., undated; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Typescript. 3p. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...)
  - Description of great English houses and gardens., undated; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Photostat of D. 3p. (see Correa de Serra. Letters.. .) From original in Mass. Hist. Soc.
  - Observations on botany., undated; 11x8-1/2; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Typescript. 3p. In Latin. (see Correa de Serra. Letters...)
  - Memoire of books forwarded to Thomas Jefferson, undated